NATHAN MCCULLOUGH: Hi.
In these clips, we're going to talk about some of the tips and tricks in order to properly winterize your vehicle.
There's also another option which you're going to really want to consider if you live in a snowy area, they're snow tires.
There are several different brands, mix and models of snow tires, and they're priced very significantly.
Generally, a snow tire will be a little thinner, and the tread will be slightly knobbier.
What that we'll do is provide more space for that snow to squish into as your tread knobs grip the ground.
Snow tires are great.
They work wonderfully in the winter time.
However, in the summertime, they wear extremely fast.
So if you opt for the snow tire option, what you're going to want to do is run your snow tires for only the months between, say, November and early March.
If you are to run your snow tires in the summertime, they will wear out extremely fast.
So, if you want to get snow tires, hang on to your old tires.
Unless your tire professional advises you that they're already gone, or worn out, or destroyed, keep them, just have them--throw--load them up in the back of your truck, or car.
Take them home.
Put them in your garage or over by the side of your house, and save them for later installation when the summertime comes.
And that's the proper way to ensure that you have a good thread surface for the winter time while driving your vehicle.